<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></title><description><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></description><link>https://johanbrook.com</link><generator>metalsmith-feed</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:49:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://johanbrook.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><author><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></author><item><title><![CDATA[The White Duck]]></title><description><![CDATA[The White Duck was, on the surface, lonely. She was not vicious, stupid, or bad in any way. She was just different from the rest of the ducks. It is not known whether it was the colour of her feathers, or lack thereof, who set her apart. Even though I am skeptical to that, it surely didn't strengthen her case.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">The White Duck</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Conditionally Composable Functions]]></title><description><![CDATA[I write a lot of Javascript at work, mostly in the Meteor framework. Our web app use a client side router, and we had this helper function for fetching a team from a slug in the route URL.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">Conditionally Composable Functions</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 15:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[On Socialising]]></title><description><![CDATA[One thing I've noticed during my past half ish year of traveling outside of Europe is the difference in how young people interact and socialise with each other, compared to the customs in my native country Sweden.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">On Socialising</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Ocean]]></title><description><![CDATA[A short ode to the ocean.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">The Ocean</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 23:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Intimate remote work]]></title><description><![CDATA[In Lookback, we've had the notion of being able to work remote as a baseline since day one. Here are some of my thoughts on the deeper end of working remote, on personal levels.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">Intimate remote work</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 15:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Shipped with fear]]></title><description><![CDATA[There is a thing that every developer has to do at some point – ship. By ship I refer to the act of deploying, pushing the button, publishing your work for a wide mass. This act is central in our industry: blog posts like this one have been written, there have been talks on the subjects, and methodologies (like Continous Delivery, Continous Integration) invented to deal with the pain points associated with shipping. Hell, there are even roles (devops, sysops) for easening the burden of moving code from one system to another. Why, oh why are we conscious and sometimes afraid of shipping our work?]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">Shipped with fear</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What's new in Safari 9]]></title><description><![CDATA[I'm attending WWDC 2015, and during the web development session, Apple's Safari team showed off what's new in Safari 9. It includes iOS style effects, such as backdrop filters and scroll snapping with CSS, ES6 updates, other CSS niceties.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">What&apos;s new in Safari 9</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 13:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pain points & Incentives]]></title><description><![CDATA[When working with building features in a product, I usually need some emotional attachment to them. You can't make them good unless you believe in them and really understand the problem you're trying to solve. This is of course Johan-stating-the-obvious, but I experienced this the other day.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">Pain points &amp; Incentives</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 14:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What's happened so far]]></title><description><![CDATA[I haven't written here for almost a year now, and some things have happened since.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">What&apos;s happened so far</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 02:04:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Redesigned & Reimagined]]></title><description><![CDATA[So I redesigned my site. It's close to one year since my last post, and I actually feel itchy to write things again (mostly for my own sake).]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">Redesigned &amp; Reimagined</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Writing contextual CSS]]></title><description><![CDATA[Organization and structure of CSS might be one of the largest difficulties for beginners as for professionals in web design. It is hard writing good CSS. It is somewhat easer with pre-processors (SCSS, LESS, Stylus), but they'll only give you the tools: it's up to you how to use them (what I can't do without is the @import feature).]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">Writing contextual CSS</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA["Master of many trades"]]></title><description><![CDATA[We hear the descriptive words psychopath and sociopath all the time, but here’s a new one: monopath. It means a person with a narrow mind, a one-track brain, a bore, a super-specialist, an expert with no other interests — in other words, the role-model of choice in the Western world.
Great text about things I've written or linked to before: how being wide in your interests and learning really is a great way of living. Personally, I am able to connect things that I previously thought were separate, building bridges between areas, and seeing things in a larger perspective, giving me a deeper understanding of the subject and thus a unique satisfaction with what I am currently doing.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">&quot;Master of many trades&quot;</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 04:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Changing perspectives and doing the crazy thing]]></title><description><![CDATA[Like it or not, but tech people often have their way of doing things. Together we've drunk the same drink telling us that "this is the way of doing things", and we repeatedly create products where we incorporate this way of thinking, which go generations back (slight over-exaggeration).]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">Changing perspectives and doing the crazy thing</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 22:38:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A symbol for sex]]></title><description><![CDATA["What is an appropriate symbol for sex?". The question I asked myself some time ago might seem somewhat trivial at first, but when you dig deeper, it reveals a bunch of sub-questions and scenarios.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">A symbol for sex</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 16:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[I don't like counting hours]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the freelance and consultancy business, you often charge per work hour. It's the rate, and then you estimate the total number of hours for a project. The estimate is ... an estimate. Estimates are seldom correct, even for senior consultants. I'm not ashamed to say that I often do an initial estimate, then almost doubling it when responding to the client. One thing I've learnt is that it's immensely better to land a project below the estimate than above.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">I don&apos;t like counting hours</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 17:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[On Scala]]></title><description><![CDATA[A friend and colleague of mine is boasting a lot about Clojure and it's productive capabilities. But I really can't wrap my head around the LISP syntax. Perhaps it's a matter of putting in time.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">On Scala</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 00:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Programming and communication]]></title><description><![CDATA[The difference between a tolerable programmer and a great programmer is not how many programming languages they know, and it’s not whether they prefer Python or Java. It’s whether they can communicate their ideas. By writing clear comments and technical specs, they let other programmers understand their code, which means other programmers can use and work with their code instead of rewriting it. Absent this, their code is worthless. By writing clear technical documentation for end users, they allow people to figure out what their code is supposed to do, which is the only way those users can see the value in their code.
 Joel Spolsky]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">Programming and communication</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 21:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tags and class names – on building flexible markup]]></title><description><![CDATA[It is said your markup should be clean and semantic. What does that mean, exactly? As few tags as possible? The correct tags for the job? Few or no ID and class attributes? At least that's been the main formula for a while now. Littering ID and class attributes over your markup has been frowned upon. But what does the alternative mean?]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">Tags and class names – on building flexible markup</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 12:14:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Object-oriented Programming and Modeling the Real World]]></title><description><![CDATA[Almost everybody begins OOP with this misconception - objects in real world directly map to OOP objects. Its maybe a good place to start but how many grow up from the initial simplistic rule - map nouns in requirements to classes. So, you end up with objects that don't really mean anything and don't do much. Naive use of UML diagrams also leads to this. Discovering abstractions is tricky. One needs to really live with requirements inside out before they present themselves.
From a Hacker News comment on  this story about Clojure programming. I've seen this myself in school, where we've gone through endless examples of OOP where the classes were a Ball, a Car, a Zebra, or other overused objects in the real world. The thing is, most programming isn't about modeling the real world, our world. When writing code you're free to do things your way, not being tied to the constraints of the real world thinking.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">Object-oriented Programming and Modeling the Real World</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 14:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How Ryan Singer builds products]]></title><description><![CDATA[Our company DNA at 37signals is make things we want, and to make them the way that we want them
 Ryan Singer
Great interview with Ryan Singer about product design.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">How Ryan Singer builds products</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Johan Brook]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 14:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>